https://www.licares.org/get-to-know-us/financials-and-policies/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy • Long Island Cares, Inc.
Agency
SupportFood BankFood DrivesFirst Stop Food PantriesChildren’s Nutrition ProgramsMobile ServicesBaxter’s Pet PantryVeterans ServicesEmergency Response and Recovery
Education and Training
Hunger 101Just Say YesNew Paths to Achievement ProgramKids United Against HungerStudent Volunteer Corps
Our LegacyNewsCareersBoard of DirectorsFinancials and Policies
Privacy PolicyGift Acceptance Policy
Solicitation PolicySign up for Email Alerts
Find
Help
Food Locator
Make a Difference
Ways to Give
BequestsCar Donation ProgramEndowment FundDonateDonate Food
Volunteer
Volunteer Registration FormStudent Volunteer Corps Registration Form
Host a Food Drive
Food Drive Registration Form9th Annual Legislative Pet Food Drive
Turn Your Music into MealsAttend an EventCorporate Giving
Corporate Heroes
Open a Soup Kitchen or PantryOpportunities for YouthAdvocate
Understand the Issues
Faces of HungerHunger GlossaryFast FactsFrequently Asked QuestionsResearch and Reports
Contact Us
Staff Directory
Facebook
Twitter
YouTube
Linkedin
Get toKnow Us
Call Us
Did you know
The elderly make up 4% of Long Island’s hungry population.
What Would You Like To Do?
Our Programs
Education and Training
Our Legacy
Careers
Board of Directors
Financials and Policies
Solicitation Policy
Sign up for Email Alerts
Student
Volunteers
Middle and high school students can join the fight against hunger.
Privacy Policy
Long Island Cares (LIC) respects the privacy of our donors, volunteers, vendors, agencies, clients, employees and website visitors. This Privacy Policy discloses practices followed by us in order to protect the privacy of your personal information that is collected by LIC.
In the course of donating to, volunteering for, accepting the services of, or doing business with LIC, you may be asked to provide your name, e-mail address, postal address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information as well as other data required by government regulations. We collect only the specific information that is necessary, and which you provide voluntarily, as a condition of your transaction with LIC.
This “personally identifiable information” becomes the property of LIC and is maintained in secure files for retention periods stipulated by our Document Retention Policy and/or is destroyed in such a manner as to prevent its unauthorized and illegal use. LIC personnel who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.
WE DO NOT SELL, RENT, OR SHARE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION WITH ANY THIRD PARTY except as specifically required by the transaction for which it was provided voluntarily to LIC.
We may use personally identifiable information: (a) to facilitate the transaction for which it was provided; (b) to respond to your inquiries or questions about our services and transactions; (c) for internal marketing purposes and as part of our donor database; (d) to provide you with additional and updated information, materials and other advertisements regarding our services; (e) to cooperate with government officials or parties in litigation under process of law, or as otherwise required by law; and/or (f) to protect the integrity and safety of our organization and its donors, volunteers, vendors, agencies, clients, employees, and web site visitors.
You may choose not to receive donation solicitations or event notifications from LIC by sending a letter to Long Island Cares, Inc., 10 Davids Drive, Hauppauge, NY 11788 or by calling the Development Office at 631-582-FOOD, ext 105. Upon receipt and processing of an “opt out” request, LIC will remove your information from any future marketing communications. You may also correct or update your personally identifiable information in this manner.
LIC also collects certain “non-personally identifiable information” when you visit our web site (http://www.licares.org), such as your browser program, your computer’s operating system, the domain name of your Internet service provider (but not your user name or e-mail address) and aggregate data about the number of visits to the web site, average time spent on the site and pages viewed. LIC uses this information for internal review only in an effort to measure site usage and improve site content. This information is never shared with other organizations for commercial or charitable purposes.
In addition, LIC does not use “cookies,” which are very small data files that are stored on your computer’s hard drive and are used to enable specific browsing features. These files do not contain, nor do they reveal, any personally identifiable information. Nevertheless, “cookies” have caused concern about the privacy of Internet browsing and LIC chooses not to use them.
LIC protects your online donation information by using online security technology provided by two acknowledged leaders in online commercial payment transactions; Authorize.net and PayPal. The donor is directed by hyperlink from our web site to to PayPal, where the donation transaction is processed.  Donations made through Authorize.net are made directly through Long Island Cares website.
The technology employed by Authorize.net and PayPal encrypts your data to avoid the decoding of information by anyone other than Authorize.net and PayPal. This technology is considered highly effective. Nevertheless, such security measures may not prevent all loss, misuse, or alteration of personal information provided by you in the transaction. LIC IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR DAMAGES OR LIABILITIES RELATING TO ANY ONLINE TRANSACTION SECURITY FAILURES.
If you provide personally identifiable information to LIC by e-mail, please be aware that normal e-mail is not encrypted. E-mail and other electronic communications may be accessed by unauthorized third parties when sent over the Internet. If you include personally identifiable information in an e-mail to LIC, you authorize us to respond to you with an unencrypted e-mail message that may contain the same or other private information about you or your request.
LIC IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR DAMAGES OR LIABILITIES RELATING TO ANY ELECTRONIC COMMUNICATIONS TO OR FROM LIC THAT ARE INTERCEPTED BY THIRD PARTIES DURING TRANSMISSION OVER THE INTERNET.
Our web site contains links to other web sites that may be of interest to our visitors.
LIC receives no income, reimbursement, or any other consideration for providing these links. While we strive to link only to web sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, LIC is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these other web sites.
LIC, at its sole discretion, reserves the right to update, revise, supplement and to otherwise modify this Privacy Policy. Changes will be effective immediately and incorporated into this Privacy Policy upon notice thereof which may be given by any reasonable means including by prompt posting to our web site (http://www.licares.org). Information received prior to a policy change will be protected by the version that was in place when the information was received.
By voluntarily providing personal information in the course of donating to, volunteering for, accepting the services of, or doing business with LIC, and by using our web site, you consent to our collection, storage, and use of your personal information according to the Privacy Policy that is in effect at that time.
Please send your questions or comments about this Privacy Policy to Long Island Cares, Inc., 10 Davids Drive, Hauppauge, NY 11788 or call the Development Office at 631-582-FOOD, ext 105.
Kids
United
Hunger education and volunteerism for younger kids.
10 Davids Drive (Harry Chapin Way)
Hauppauge, NY 11788-2039
P: 631-582-FOOD (3663)
F: 631-273-2184
Email: info@licares.org
EIN: 11-2524512
Long Island Cares is a 501(c)(3) registered charity
© 2020 Long Island Cares. All rights reserved.
